The transpose convolution is
a key part of the
unit architecture.
How do you take a
two-by-two inputs
and blow it up into a four-
by-four-dimensional output?
The transpose convolution
lets you do that.
Let's dig into the details.
You're familiar with the
normal convolution in which
a typical layer of
a new network may
input a six by six
by three image,
convolve that with a set of, say,
three by three by three filters
and if you have five of these,
then you end up with an output
that is four by four by five.
A transpose convolution
looks a bit difference.
You might inputs a two-by-two,
said that activation,
convolve that with a
three by three filter,
and end up with an output
that is four by four,
that's bigger than
the original inputs.
Let's step through a
more detailed example
of how this works.
In this example,
we're going to take
a two-by-two inputs like they're
shown on the left
and we want to end
up with a four by four outputs.
But to go from two-by-two
to four-by-four,
I'm going to choose to use
a filter that is three by three.
The filter is f by f,
and I'm going to
choose three by three
and let's say that's
the filter we will use.
I'm also going to use
a padding p is equal to
one and in the outputs,
I'm going to apply,
that's one p padding,
,and then finally,
the last parameter,
I'm going to use
a stride s equal to
two for this example.
Let's see how the transpose
convolution will work.
In the regular convolution,
you would take the
filter and place it on
top of the inputs and
then multiply and sum up.
In the transpose convolution,
instead of placing the
filter on the input,
you would instead place
a filter on the output.
Let me illustrate that
by mechanically stepping
through the steps of
the transpose
convolution calculation.
Let's starts with
this upper left entry
of the input, which is a two.
We are going to take
this number two and
multiply it by every
single value in
the filter and we're going
to take the output
which is three by
three and paste it
in this position.
Now, the padding area isn't
going to contain any values.
What we're going
to end up doing is
ignore this paddy
region and just throw
in four values in the
red highlighted area
and specifically,
the upper left entry is zero
times two, so that's zero.
The second entry is one
times two, that is two.
Down here is two times two,
that's four, and then over here
is one times two so
that's equal to two.
Next, let's look at
the second entry of the
input which is a one.
I'm going to switch to
green pen for this.
Once again, we're going
to take a one and
multiply by one every single
elements of the filter,
because we're using
a stride of two,
we're now going to
shift to box in which
we copy the numbers
over by two steps.
Again, we'll ignore the area
which is in the padding and
the only area that
we need to copy
the numbers over is
this green shaded area.
You may notice that there is
some overlap between the
places where we copy
the red-colored version
of the filter and
the green version
and we cannot simply
copy the green value
over the red one.
Where the red and the
green boxes overlap,
you add two values together.
Where there's already a
two from the first
weighted filter,
you add to it this first
value from the green
region which is also two.
You end up with two plus two.
The next entry, zero
times one is zero,
then you have one, two
plus zero times one,
so two plus zero followed by two,
followed by one and again,
we shifted two squares over from
the red box here to the green box
here because it using
a stride of two.
Next, let's look at
the lower-left entry of
the input, which is three.
We'll take the filter,
multiply every element by three
and we've gone down
by one step here.
We're going to go down
by two steps here.
We will be filling in
our numbers in this
three by three square
and you find that
the numbers you copying
over are two times three,
which is six, one times three,
which is three, zero times three,
which is zero, and so on,
three, six, three
,and then lastly,
let's go into the last input
element, which is two.
We will multiply every
elements of the filter by
two and add them to
this block and you
end up with adding
one times two which is plus two,
and so on for the
rest of the elements.
The final step is to
take all the numbers in
these four by four matrix of
values in the 16 values
and add them up.
You end up with zero here,
two plus two is four, zero, one,
four plus six is 10,
two plus zero plus three
plus two is seven,
two plus four is six.
I know this looks like a little
bit of a mess because I'm
writing on top of
things there is zero,
three plus four was
seven, zero, two,
six, three plus zero was three,
four, two, hence that's
your four-by-four outputs.
In case you're wondering why
do we have to do it this way,
I think there are
multiple possible ways to
take small inputs and turn
it into bigger outputs,
but the transpose convolution
happens to be one that is
effective and when you learn
all the parameters
of the filter here,
this turns out to give good
results when you put this in
the context of the union which
is the learning
algorithm will use now.
Let's go back and keep
on building the unit.
In this video, we step
through step-by-step how
the transpose convolution
lets you take a small input,
say two-by-two, and blow
it up into larger output,
say four by four.
This is the key building block
of the unit architecture
which you get to implement
and play within
this week's programming
exercises well.
Now that you understand
a transpose convolution,
let's take this
building block you now
have and see how it fits into
the overall unit architecture
that you can use for
semantic segmentation.
Let's go on to the next video.